Earlier you saw an example of noise in an image of San Francisco City Hall.
说到图像噪声 之前那张旧金山市政大厅图就有所涉及
This noise is generally seen as speckles or discoloration in
噪声通常就是图像的斑点或变色部分
an image and it doesn't contain any useful information.
不含任何有用信息
It might even mess with processing steps such as
甚至会影响处理操作
an edge detection when high pass filters can amplify noise if it's not removed first.
比如在边缘检测时 如果没有先解决噪声 高通过滤器就会把噪声强化
The most common way to remove noise is by using a low pass filter.
低通过滤器是噪声最常见的解决方式
These filters block certain high frequency content and
这类过滤器能阻挡特定高频部分
effectively blur or smooth the appearance of an image,
有效模糊图像或使图像平滑起来
and this reduces high frequency noise.
从而减少高频噪声
An example where this is very useful is in medical images which typically have
这种过滤器的实用性在医学影像里淋漓尽致地体现了出来
noise that's produced either by the imagery machinery or by a moving human subject.
这类图像通常都会因为影像设备或人体移动而产生噪声
Let's take a closer look at this cross-sectional image of a human brain.
我们来仔细讲讲这张人脑横断面图
We can clearly see the outline of a skull and brain but
我们可以明显看到头骨和大脑的轮廓
we also see a lot of sort of salt and pepper speckle,
但也可以看到很多盐粒或胡椒粒似的斑点
and this is high frequency noise.
这就是高频噪声
You can imagine if we applied a high pass filter with the goal of detecting edges,
你可以想象一下 如果我们用高通滤波镜来检测边缘
we would detect and amplify a lot of this spotty noise.
不仅会检测到许多噪声 还会强化它们
We can reduce this noise by taking a kind of average between neighboring pixels so
要降噪 我们可以取相邻像素的均值
that there are not such big jumps in intensity especially in small areas.
从而避免强度突变 特别是小范围突变
This averaging of pixels in space is equivalent to
而这种取空间像素均值的做法
implementing a low pass filter that blocks high frequency noise.
同应用低通过滤器来过滤高频噪声是一样的
Let's see an example of a common kernel that does this.
我们来看一个例子 用普通核来降噪
The first and simplest is the averaging filter.
第一个也是最简单的一个 均值过滤器
It's a three by three kernel that weights are sent to
这是个三乘三的核
pixel and its surrounding pixels all the same.
核会赋予中心像素及其相邻像素一样的权重
Low pass filters typically take an average and not a difference as high pass filters do.
低通过滤器通常会取均值 不像高通过滤器取的是差值
So their components should all add up to one.
因此低通过滤器的元素加起来应该为 1
This will preserve the image brightness and make sure
这就能保留图像的亮度
that it doesn't get brighter or darker overall.
确保图像不会变亮或变暗
But we can see that the components of this kernel add up to nine.
但我们可以看到 这个核的元素加起来等于 9
So we need to normalize by dividing the total value of the kernel by nine.
所以我们需要进行归一化处理 也就是将核值总和除以 9
Then our total sum becomes one.
于是最终结果就等于 1 了
Now let's go back to our main image and see what a convolution looks like between
现在回到医学影像上来 观察图像 F (x , y) 和这个核 K
the image F of XY and the kernel K. Here's a zoomed in portion of the image.
的卷积情况 这里放大了图像的某一部分
To perform convolution we put
为了进行卷积
our three by three kernel on top of each pixel in our image.
我们需要把这个三乘三的核分别放到图像的每个像素上
I'll choose this dark one with a value of 40 as our center pixel.
我选这个值为 40 的黑像素作为中心像素
Then looking at all the values in this three by three square,
观察三乘三方块里的所有值
we perform multiplication in pairs using the weights in
将核里的权重
our kernel to multiply all the pixel values.
与相应的像素两两相乘
In this case, we're multiplying all the values by one and summing them up.
因此 我们将所有值分别乘以 1 然后相加
Our last step will be dividing by nine to normalize the image
最后将总和除以 9 将图像归一化
and get a corresponding output pixel value, 85.
从而得到要输出的像素值 85
We can see that this is just an average of
我们可以发现 这就是中心像素
the center pixel and its surrounding neighbor pixels.
与其相邻像素的均值
Since the surrounding pixels are mostly brighter than the center pixel,
由于相邻像素大多比中心像素亮
the new output pixel value is brighter too.
所以新输出的像素值也会更亮
If we do this with all the pixels in this image,
如果对整张图像的所有像素进行同样的均值处理
we'll get an average to smoothed out image with fewer abrupt changes in intensity.
我们就能使图像变得平滑 图像里的强度突变也会变少
This can be useful for blowing out noise or making
这有利于减少噪声
a background area within a certain intensity range look more uniform.
或使处于一定强度范围的背景区域看起来更加平滑
In fact, this sort of filter is even used in
实际上 这类过滤器在 Photoshop 里也有应用
Photoshop to soften and blur parts of an image.
可对图像的某一部分进行柔化或模糊处理
Next, let's see how to do this in code.
接下来我们来讲怎么编写代码